sciencemadesimple.com 2017-09-03

# Privacy Policy - Science Made Simple

## Privacy Policy for Science Made Simple

This site is owned and operated by Science Made Simple, Inc. Your personal privacy and security are very importance to us, and we want to make sure you understand what kinds of information we collect and how we use it.

### COPPA Compliance - Collecting Information from Children

Consistent with the Federal Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), Science Made Simple, Inc. will never knowingly request or collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without requesting parental consent. 

### Information We Collect

We may collect personally identifiable information from you when you place an order, subscribe to our newsletter, fill out a contact form or contact us by e-mail. You may, however, visit our site anonymously without providing personal information.

When placing an order, you will be asked to enter your name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number and credit card information via a secure server. 

### How We Use Your Information

Information we collect from you may be used to process your order, e-mail your purchased subscription or articles to you, send you our free opt-in newsletter, improve our website and customer service, and personalize your experience.

Your information, whether public or private, will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company without your consent, other than for the express purpose of delivering the purchased product or service requested.

The e-mail address you provide for order processing may be used to send you information and updates pertaining to your order, in addition to receiving occasional company news, updates, related product or service information, etc.

The e-mail address you provide when requesting information or contacting us for any other reason, may be used to send you information regarding your request, in addition to receiving occasional company news, updates, related product or service information, etc.

We will honor all e-mail unsubscribe requests. Detailed unsubscribe instructions can be found at the bottom of each e-mail, or use our [online contact form](http://www.sciencemadesimple.com/contactus.html) for removal requests. 

### Protecting Your Information

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you place an order, or enter or submit your personal information. 

We use a secure server to process your credit card order. All sensitive financial and credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our payment gateway provider's database. Access to this data is restricted, and the data is kept confidential. Your financial information is not stored on our servers. 

### Use of Cookies

Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your web browser that enable the sites or service providers systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information.

We use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart and compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may contract with third-party service providers to assist us in better understanding our site visitors. These service providers are not permitted to use the information collected on our behalf except to help us conduct and improve our business.

### Disclosing Information to Outside Parties

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

### Third Party Links and Advertisements

To provide you with information and offers that may be of interest to you, we have relationships with other companies that place advertisements or links on our web pages. As a result of your visit to our site, these companies may collect information such as your domain type, your IP address and clickstream information. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites. For further information, please consult the privacy policies of: Google.com, Amazon.com and Verio.com. 

Google, as a third party vendor, uses DART cookies to serve ads on our site, which enables Google to serve ads to you based on your visit to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google Ad and Content Network privacy policy page.

### Terms and Conditions

Please also visit our Terms and Conditions section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our website at <http://www.sciencemadesimple.com/termsofservice.html>

### Your Consent

By using our site, you consent to our online privacy policy as described on this page.

### Changes to our Privacy Policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page, and/or update the Privacy Policy modification date below. 

This policy was last modified on 10/24/13.

### Contacting Us

If you have any questions regarding this privacy policy, or any other questions, you may contact us using the methods below:

Online using our [contact form](http://www.sciencemadesimple.com/contactus.html)

Or by mail at   
Science Made Simple, Inc.   
PO Box 503   
Voorhees, NJ 08043
